VYSHNAVI KARUMURU

Bloomington, IL – 61704 | +1 305 427 1701 | vkaru001@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

With 3 years of effective contributions as a skilled frontend developer, I've implemented the web applications using JavaScript and ReactJS. I recently graduated master's in computer and information sciences in Florida International University obtaining skills for the industry requirements. I aspire to make valuable contributions by being updated with new technologies and approaches while utilizing my experience to take challenges and lay the foundation for a successful career.

KEY SKILLS

- Programing Languages: Java, Python; Web Technologies: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript
- Frameworks: ReactJS, NextJS; API: REST API; Version control: GitHub
- Database Servers: MySQL, PostgreSQL; Cloud Technologies: Azure, AWS
- Machine Learning Techniques: Linear Discriminant Analysis, Random Forest, Logistic Regression, Scikit, Seaborn, Tesseract
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Problem Solving, Teamwork, Collaboration, Time Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Suvarna TechnoSoft, Front-end Developer, Full Time

Jan 2020 - July 2022

- Built end-to-end front-end websites for Outpatient Management in hospitals using JavaScript and ReactJS.
- Implemented various screens for front end using **React.js** for DOM manipulation and used various reusable components and functionalities from **React Hooks**, **NPM and Redux**.
- Assisted in creating multiple dynamic widgets to improve the capture and display of doctor availability, reducing appointment approval time for customers by 40%.
- Achieved a 30% reduction in website load times through performance optimization techniques.
- Implemented a floating chatbot interface for couple of hospitals for customer support.
- Developed Azure Active Directory (AAD) authentication and OAuth authorization for API security.
- Collaborated with BA, QA, and Dev team to conduct unit testing, ensuring high-quality and bug-free deliverables.

Suvarna TechnoSoft, Web Developer, Intern

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developed multiple proof-of-concepts (POCs) by building various login portals and Product UI builder screens for Outpatient Management's web applications using **HTML**, **CSS3**, **JavaScript**, **and React**.
- Implemented optimized git strategies to get rid of 90% merge conflicts and version release managements.
- Developed and implemented new UI features and components while resolving existing UI bugs before stage release.

EDUCATION

Florida International University, Miami, United States

Aug 2022 – Dec 2023

MS in Computer Science (CGPA – 3.63, Courses – DBMS, Data Mining, and Introduction to Algorithms)

MLR Institute of Technology, Hyderabad, India

July 2017 - June 2021

BTECH in Information Technology (CGPA - 3.30, Courses - Machine Learning, Java, Web Technologies)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Confusion Restaurant Stimulation

- Developed a desktop application for restaurant website stimulation using React and JavaScript features a single page application (SPA) with responsive design and created some necessary reusable components.
- Leveraging Redux, controlled forms, and Fetch for client-server communication using Rest API, integrating elements of the Flux architecture.

Codex

- Built a JavaScript AI chat application using OpenAI machine learning model and integrated Advanced GPT-3 model API for communication with the AI.
- Implemented the ability to ask the AI for help with programming languages and code translation with the technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, and OpenAI APIs.

License Plate Recognition

- Developed a desktop application using Image Processing Technology and Python that is used in various security and traffic applications to identify vehicles by their license plates.
- Helps to extract license plates from vehicle images using Python, Tensor Flow, and Keras image processing methods, and retrieves the license number from the extracted license plate.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Coursera: Front-End Web Development with React
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals and Data Fundamentals
- Udemy: Python Certified